准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
洗衣也疯狂
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
收获我作物
Harvesting my crops
呀塔塔塔
Ya-ta-ta-ta
辣椒品相好
Peppers look delish
呀塔塔塔
Ya-ta-ta-ta
香蕉椒也是
Banana peppers too
呀塔塔
Ya-ta-ta
塔
Ta
早安  章鱼哥
Good morning, Squidward
呀塔塔塔
Ya-ta-ta-ta
呀塔塔塔个屁
Ya-ta-ta-ta my foot
你害我把墨
You made me ink
喷到我最后一件干净衬衣上了
on my last clean shirt
现在不得不去自助洗衣店了
Now I have to go to the laundromat
自助洗衣店吗
The laundromat?
那可是个神奇的地方
Why, that's a magical place
可以把所有污垢和灰尘都洗掉
where all filth and grime is washed away
让衣服焕然一新
making clothes spring fresh
我家里有不少脏衣服得洗一下烘一下
I have a lot of filthy clothes that need a spin and dry
我也要去洗衣服
I'll do my laundry too
等我一下  章鱼哥
Wait for me, Squidward
我就在这等
I'll wait right here
洗刷刷
章鱼哥
Squidward
等等我
Wait for me
慢点  海绵宝宝
Slow down, SpongeBob
全裤头村的人今天都来洗衣服吗
Is everyone in town doing their laundry today?
早知道就凌晨两点没人的时候过来了
I should've come at 2 a.m. when it's empty
可那样就没法认识我的臭袜朋友了
But then you wouldn't get to meet my stinky sock friend
臭袜朋友
Stinky sock friend?
你到底在扯什么
What in the world are you talking about?
认真的吗
Seriously?
有个空的洗衣机
An open machine
谢谢你帮我占洗衣机  章鱼哥
Thanks for holding the washer for me, Squidward
派大星  你没穿衣服
Patrick, you're naked
那我就需要这个
Then I'm gonna need this
快还我
Give me that
改穿这个
Take this instead
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
我竟能有这般荣幸
I don't believe I've had the pleasure
你好笨
You're so silly
好强的臭味
That is one strong stink
好啊  比就比
Oh yeah, let's do this
早知道就喷点
Maybe I should have worn
除臭剂了
deodorant
我能借用一下吗
Can I borrow this a sec?
谢了
Thanks
珊迪
Hey, Sandy
我才是下一个排队的
I'm next in line
别插队
No cut-sies
我不需要洗衣机  章鱼哥
I don't need a machine, Squidward
只要一点肥皂就行了
I just need a little soap
干净得不得了
Clean as a hog-whistle
再见  章鱼哥
So long, Squidward
小猪猪  该来洗澡了
Okay, little piggy, time for a bath
麻烦结账
Check please
太神了
Amazing
太神
Ama
了
Zing
太香了
Mmm-mazing
我都忘了
I forgot
我的皮肤只能干洗
My skin is dry clean only
总算要来洗掉这污渍了
Finally, time to extract this stain
你手上那是什么  章鱼哥
Whatcha got there, Squidward?
可以去除烦人的污渍
It removes annoying stains
但不幸的是
Unfortunately for me
它没法去除烦人的海绵
it doesn't remove annoying sponges
洗掉吧  这该死的污点
Out, darn spot
[ 引自莎士比亚《麦克白》 ]
污渍不见了
The stain is gone
你穿上去的样子真帅气
That looks marvelous on you
来看看背面吧
Let's see the back
章鱼哥
Squidward?
你得来件更大的衬衣
You're gonna need a bigger shirt
怎么
What the?
真希望我能帮上忙
I wish there was something I could do to help
等一下
Wait a second
用力点搓  章鱼哥
Scrub harder, Squidward
感觉你清理实验器材的方式不正规
Seems like an unorthodox way
of cleaning your lab equipment
少挖苦我了
Stop busting my antenna
这样子更快  而且只要两毛五
This is quicker and it only costs a quarter
多半是器材放得不均匀导致的振动
Maybe it's an unbalanced load
也有可能是你忘了
Or maybe you forgot
给试管上面的变异配方冲干净
to rinse those mutation formulas off those test tubes
妈啊
Mommy
事情老被你说中  你就不觉得烦吗
Don't you ever get tired of being right?
我的裤腿
My pant leg
小蒂  乖一点
Tilly, be nice
别去咬那个上过浆的衬衣
Leave that starched shirt alone
成功了
It worked
墨渍洗掉了
The ink spot is gone
我就知道你能行
I knew you could do it
章鱼哥
Squidward
不会吧
Oh no
墨渍跑我背心去了
The spot is on my undershirt
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
干嘛
What?
好办法  海绵宝宝
Good idea, SpongeBob
就用这淀粉浆彻底定住那滩墨渍
I'll hold that spot in place
once and for all with this starch
说晚安吧  墨渍
Say goodnight, Spot
洗衣机死掉了
The washing machine is dead
我的衣服又干净到能发光
And my clothes are sparkling clean
完事了
Welp, that's done
回去打理我的秋海棠
Back to my begonias
他除掉了怪物
He killed the monster
他救了我们的命
He saved our lives
他是我们的英雄
He's our hero
没没没
No, no, no, no
我什么都没干啊
I didn't do anything
我什么人都没救
I didn't save anyone
你也是我的英雄  章鱼哥
You're my hero too, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
我只想回家
I just wanna go home
我想今天大家都学到了一课
I think we all learned a lesson here today
而我对此写了一首歌
and I wrote a song about it
它是这么唱的
It goes a little something like this
开始吧
Hit it
洗衣烘干
Wash and dry
我的天
My oh my
肥皂泡沫进我眼
I got soapsuds in my eye
袜子飞
Socks will fly
污渍灭
Stains will die
大家一起来烘干
Everybody Tumble Dry
裙子净
Skirts are clean
裤子蒸
Pants are steamed
拿出机器正新鲜
Fresh out of the dang machine
漂白衣服
Bleach your clothes
泡紧身裤
Soak your hose
洗衣就是这么办
This is how a washer goes
咕噜转转拉咔咔咔嘎
Glug Glug, Spin Spin Ra-Kakakaka Glug
咕噜转转拉咔咔咔咔
Glug Glug, Spin Spin Ra-Kakakaka
洗衣烘干我不骗
Wash and Dry, I won't lie
我等不及说再见
I can't wait to say goodbye
咕噜转转拜拜拜拜拜
Glug Glug, Spin Spin Bye-Bubububye
章鱼哥  等等我
Squidward, wait for me
拜拜拜拜拜
Bye-Bubububye
只是墨水而已
It's just ink
我会清理掉的
I'll clean it up
想见见我的小猪猪吗
Would you like to meet my piggy?
捉猪大作战
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我在送外卖
I'm delivering
我在送外卖  我在送外卖
I'm delivering, I'm delivering
我在送外卖
I'm delivering
滚出我家门廊  政府官员
Off my porch, government man
不然我就把你戳得浑身是洞
Or I'll poke you full of holes
别戳
Don't poke
我身上已经有洞了
I already have holes
表明你的来意
State your business
蟹堡王外卖
Food delivery from the Krusty Krab
给你  尊贵的客人
Here you go, valued customer
看来情况属实
I reckon that checks out
来看看
Let's see here
你到底是在耍什么花招
What in tarnation are ya trying to pull here
你个骗人精
ya skilamalink
有什么问题吗  先生
Is there something wrong, sir?
你少给了我的免费餐巾纸
You cheated me out of my free napkin
我明明带了餐巾纸  还放进了
I thought I grabbed napkins and put 'em in the
袋子里
bag
你害我没得选
You leave me no choice
我要
I'm gonna
写封长长的泄愤信
write a long angry letter
你在这等着
You wait here
不准用你肮脏的城市居民手碰我东西
and don't touch my things
with yer filthy city-dweller hands
边等边到处看看没什么问题吧
I guess there's no harm in looking around while I wait
只要管好自己的手就行了
As long as I keep my hands to myself
有个谷仓
A barn
那是什么声音
What's that noise?
获奖虫猪  禁止入内
"Prize worm-hog, stay out"
幸好我不是获奖虫猪
Good thing I'm not a prize worm-hog
我的城市居民手差点就碰到了
I almost touched it with my filthy city-dweller hands
不过老头简金斯可没有说
But Old Man Jenkins didn't say anything
我超干净的脚不能碰
about my super clean feet
不好意思
Excuse me?
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
派大星
Patrick?
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我在帮老头简金斯给获奖虫猪做准备
I'm helping Old Man Jenkins get his prize worm-hog ready
去参加县集市
for the county fair
看看这地方
Check this place out
有这玩意
There's this stuff
有个梳妆台
There's a makeup station
这些美照拍的是获奖虫猪吗
Is that the prize worm-hog
in all these beautiful pictures?
对  它的名字叫碧拉
Yeah, her name is Beulah
好可爱的名字
What a lovely name
这些都是你负责做的吗
And you're in charge of all this?
没  我只负责给泥巴保暖
No, I just keep the mud warm
特别暖
Really warm
碧拉在哪
Where's Beulah?
它在美美的枕头上美美地睡午觉
She's fancy napping on her fancy pillows
抱歉跟你说一下  派大星
I hate to tell you, Patrick
它不在那里
but she's not there
它不见了
She's gone
看
Look
它的围栏开着
Her pen is open
大门也开着
And so's the front door
老头简金斯一定会特别生气
Old Man Jenkins is gonna be so mad
他会把我给戳得浑身是洞
He's gonna poke me full of holes
我长长的泄愤信写完了
I finished my long angry letter
要怎么办
What are we gonna do?
那个送外卖的海绵呢
Where is that delivery sponge?
他最好跑去我谷仓里偷看
He better not've gone a-peeping in my barn
不准碰我美丽的碧拉
You keep your hands off my beautiful Beulah
我没碰它  只是在
I wasn't touching her, I was just, uh
欣赏它的美貌
admiring her beauty
啊对  我是说
Oh yeah, I mean
哪里有点不对劲
Something ain't right here
应该是你没错
I guess it's you
怎么
What the?
你们两个城市佬想骗我
You two city slickers tried to hoodwink me
碧拉呢
Where's Beulah?
我们不是故意要放碧拉走的
We didn't mean to let Beulah out
对不起
We're sorry
别把我们戳得浑身是洞
Don't poke us full of holes
够了
Enough
既然是你们俩丢了它
You two lost her
那你们俩就得帮我找到它
and you two are gonna help me find her
一小时后
这办法完全不对
We're going about this all wrong
该实行B计划了
Time to go to plan B
是放弃吗
Give up?
不对  你个傻子
No, ya idjit
是要设陷阱
We set traps
犹如蹄缝间的泥土
Like mud through cloven hooves
这就是  猪圈日常
these are the Days of our Sties
猪圈日常
老头简金斯  我们设好了
Okay, Old Man Jenkins, we've finished our
你们干什么
What are you doing?
对啊  应该是要设陷阱才对的
Yeah, we're supposed to be making traps
不是睡午觉
not taking naps
这就是陷阱  呆头
This is the trap, ya mouth-breathers
等到碧拉听到它最爱的肥皂剧
When Beulah hears her favorite soap opree
它就会爬上床来看
she'll climb in bed to watch it
爽到动都不会动了
and be too comfortable to move
等它爽了就抓住它
The ol' comfort and catch
给我看看你们的陷阱
Now show me your traps
这是我的陷阱
Here's my trap
没人能拒绝得了蟹黄堡
No one can resist Krabby Patties
看看我的陷阱
Look at my trap
踩上去
等到碧拉踩上去
When Beulah steps here
就会触发这根尖刺树枝
it triggers this spiked branch
然后嘭得一下
and bammo
晚餐就有猪排吃了
It's pork chops for dinner
只准设有人道的陷阱
Humane traps only
是要活捉它  不是要它没命
We're trying to catch her, not end her life
那行
Fine
可我还是很饿
But I'm still hungry
等等
Wait
听到没有
Did you hear that?
我的陷阱
My trap
成功了
It worked
捉到了
Gotcha
早知道就挑个冷门点的肥皂剧了
I should have picked a less popular soap opree
是我的陷阱
That's my trap
派大星
Patrick
那些可是给碧拉的
Those were for Beulah
好了  我受够了
Alright, I've had enough
怎么了
What?
踩上去
枕头
Pillow
没
didn't
效果
help
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你不知怎的好像比之前更生气了
Somehow you seem angrier than before
我不捉碧拉了
I'm done huntin' for Beulah
现在我要捉你们两个
Now I'm huntin' you two
戳得浑身是洞
full of holes
我分不清他的邪恶笑声是哪传来的了
I can't tell what direction
his evil laughter is coming from
他无处不在
He's everywhere
这应该能绊倒他们
This'll trip them up
什么
What?
他们跑哪去了
Where'd they go?
待在这里应该就安全了
We should be safe in here
可以躲进老头简金斯的胡子里
in Old Man Jenkins' beard
几个月后
胡子里来安家
Home, home in a beard
这里胡须胡茬都奇葩
Where the whiskers and stubble are weird
知道吗  派大星哥们
You knows what, Brother Patrick?
这简单的生活真平静
This simple life is so calmin'
我都忘记我们先前逃什么了
I forgot what we was runnin' from
所以你觉得我们先前是在逃什么玩意
So you reckon we was runnin' from somethin'?
又来了
There it is again
连着几个月都听见自己胡子里有怪声
I've been hearing strange sounds
from my whiskers for months now
一定是那些混蛋
I bet it's those punks
躲在我的胡子里面
They're hiding in my beard
我要进去
I'm goin' in
到你下了  派大星哥们
Your move, Brother Patrick
抽牌吧
Go fish
抓到你们这群害虫了
Gotcha, varmints
老头简金斯
Old Man Jenkins
虽然你们跑得快
You two may be fast
但我还有一样杀手锏
but I got one more trick up my trousers
我要把你们熏出来
I'm gonna smoke you out
你们迟早都会被我抓到  白痴
It's just a matter of time, idjits
不好
Oh no
已经穷途末路了
It's the end of the line
你们这回逃不掉的
You're not escaping this time
我们大家都逃不掉
I don't think any of us are escaping
看
Look
看  是我的碧拉
Look, it's my Beulah
我着火了
I'm on fire
碧拉
Beulah?
真的是你
It is you
你之前上哪去了
Where were you?
我写泄愤信写得太入迷了
I got so caught up in my angry letters
所以你就去集市
that you went to the fair
自己参赛了吗
and entered the contest on your own?
快看
And look
你得了第一名
You won first prize
等下
Wait
给你
Here you go
可以用这张蟹堡王餐巾纸擦脸
You can dry your face with this Krusty Krab napkin
原来我的餐巾纸一直都在你身上吗
You had my napkin this whole time?
肯定是在我另一边口袋
Must've been in my other pocket
跑吧
Run